Guide to the Jaime Davidovich Collection MSS.155
Fales Library and Special Collections
Works of art.; New York (N.Y.).; Black-and-white photographs.; Color photographs.; Correspondence.; Performance artists.; Color negatives.; Black-and-white negatives.; Performance art -- United States.; Contact sheets.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Cable television -- Access; Art, Modern -- 20th century; Cleveland (Ohio); Exhibition catalogs.; Conceptual art.; Buenos Aires (Argentina); Video art.; Artists and community -- United States; Fluxus (Group of artists); Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Video recordings.; Public-access television.; American Museum of the Moving Image; University of Iowa; Artists' Television Network; SoHo Television; Maciunas, George, 1931-1978; Matta-Clark, Gordon, 1943-1978; Everson Museum of Art
- Series I: Jaime Davidovich Art Files
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I: Jaime Davidovich Art Files contains materials related to Jaime Davidovich's career as a visual artist. The series is divided into eleven subseries:
  Subseries A: Project Proposals includes descriptions, abstracts, and proposals for artworks.
  Subseries B: Production contains notes, preliminary research on sites, photo-documentation of finished projects.
  Subseries C: Works on Paper incorporates completed works on paper by Jaime Davidovich.
  Subseries D: Exhibition Catalogues and Press includes catalogues, press releases, publicity, and press for exhibitions featuring Jaime Davidovich's work.
  Subseries E: Correspondence, incorporates letters, faxes, emails, and telegrams from and to Jaime Davidovich.
  Subseries F: Publications written by Jaime Davidovich includes essays as well as published visual works.
  Subseries G: Publications designed by Jaime Davidovich contains mockups and design proofs for magazines, books, and publicity materials.
  Subseries H: Teaching and Presentations includes photographs, notes, and other materials connected to teaching, conferences, and other public presentations.
  Subseries I: Photographs of Jaime Davidovich includes artist portraits, video stills, and candid photography.
  Subseries J: Press, Interviews, and Essays about Jaime Davidovich contains writing that is not connected to a particular exhibit.
  - Subseries A: Project Proposals
    - "Road". Description of project created with Akron Art Institute, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - State Building, proposal for main sculpture lobby., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "New York Project" proposal to WNET-TV, Channel 13., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Interior" description of videotape produced at Synapse Video Center., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Taped Room Project" at MoMA Project Room, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Taped and Live" Video art installation proposal, Whitney Biennial, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The Gap", submission to Ithaca Video Festival, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Evita project description, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Proposed contribution to The New Museum's anthology of artists' writing, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Entry form for Festival Internacional de Video y Artes Electronicas in Buenos Aires., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Proposal for "Cross" installation at the Museo Latino., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Video paintings description, edited by Janet Heit., 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Mixed Blessings" Installation proposal, Bronx Museum, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "La Tierra Prometida" ICI exhibit description., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Torn Identity" project abstract., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Video Installations promotape abstract., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Whitney Museum Taped Project proposal, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Black and white contact and prints of proposed installation at the Cleveland Museum of Art., undated (Box 1, Folder 17A)
  - Subseries B: Production Materials
    - Black and white photographs of paintings. No photographer designated., 1953-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Black and white photographs of paintings, Argentina. Photographs by Nanny Roitman, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Black and white photograph of oil painting. Photograph by Diego Forero., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Black and white photographs of oil paintings. [inc. labels "Painting 1960"], 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Black and white photographs and negative of painting with string., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Black and white painting and photograph collage, negative, and photograph., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Color slides of Jaime Davidovich's work, paintings and documentation of exhibitions., 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Black and white photographs documentating, tape, drape, and line artwork at various venues throughout the 1970s (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Black and white photographs documenting the Taped Projects., 1970-1974 (Box Binder 2, Folder data_value_missing_13546eccb3b8636904403bdf04fd7a94)
    - Black and white photographs of planning collages for J. Carroll show., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Black and white photographs of Jaime Davidovich installing the J. Carroll show., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Black and white negatives and photographs documenting the J. Carroll Show., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Black and white negatives and photographs documenting the J. Carroll Show., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Lake Erie "Wall Project", part of the Experiments in Art and Technology show. Technical data., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Black and white negatives and photographs documenting the Lake Erie "Wall Project", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Black and white negatives and phtoographs documenting the EAT show at Lake Erie Colelge., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Drake University Iberamerican Celebration., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Black and white negatives and prints, study for Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Black and white negatives, contact sheet, and print for Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Black and white negatives. Documentation of Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Black and white negatives and prints, documentation of Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Black and white negatives and contact sheets, documentation of Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Black and white negatives. Documentation of Cleveland Taped Sidewalk Project., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - ACLU Benefit II, notes on Jaime Davidovich's contribution to the show., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Large format black and white negatives and prints. Preparation for Whitney Museum "Taped Wall Project", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Black and white photographs, labeled "Studio", 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Documentatioin of artworks, 1973. Includes clippings and images. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Akron Invitational, black and white negatives and photo-documentation., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bykert Gallery, "Ceiling Project" artist's notes and black and white photographs., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Euclid Ave. Bridge Project notes and black and white photographs., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Governor's Mansion, artist's notes and black and white photographs., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - 6 Artists show at the New Gallery in Cleveland. Black and white negatives, prints, and notes., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Whitney Bienial, "Taped Wall Project" black and white photographs., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Documentation of artworks, 1974. Includes announcments, photographs and descriptions., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "Arte de Systemas en Latnioamerica" Black and white photographs of exhibit in Belgium., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - State Building, preparatory materials including diagrams and photographs., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Video Photos, 1974. Black and white negatives and contact sheet. (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Video Photos, 1974. Black and white negatives and transparency contact sheet. (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Video Photos, 1974. collected photographs and negatives. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Video Photos, 1974, color stills (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "Art Today: USA" in Tehran and Lorain County College black and white negatives, photographs, and copies of contact sheets., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - No Folder (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Road" black and white photographic video still prints, black and white contact sheets, color snapshots dated 1975, and promotional invite for Lorain County communicty college exhibition. (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "Baseboard" black and white still from color video With Diane Brown Gallery identification on reverse., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - 3 Mercer Street, black and white contact sheets. Videotape of Stuart Sherman's 5th Spectacle., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - 3 Mercer St. Black and white negatives, contact sheets and photographs. Videotape of Stuart Sherman's 5th Spectacle., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - 3 Mercer St. videotape of Stuart Sherman's 5th Spectacle. Black and white negatives and photographs- some photographs have portions cut out., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - 3 Mercer St. Videotape of Stuart Sherman's 5th Spectacle. Notes and publicity materials., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - 3 Mercer St. videotape of Stuart Sherman's 5the Spectacle. Black and white negatives and photographs- some photogrpahs have portions cut out., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - USIA Program, color negatives., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - USIA Program, color snapshots., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "Interior" black and white negatives., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - "Interior" video stills: black and white negatives and contact sheets., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - "Interior Windows" two large format negatives of video stills., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - "Two Windows" black and white video stills and annotated project abstract., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Everson Museum, artist notes including drafts of a news release, an invitation, and a project conceptualization., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Everson Museum, installation and production materials and notes., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Everson Museum black and white negatives and photographs., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Everson Musuem black and white negatives, contact sheet, and photographs., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Everson Museum, black and white negatives and photograph., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Everson Museum. Black and white negatives, contact sheet, and photograph., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Everson Museum, photocopies of contact sheets and prints., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Video in SITV performance piece called "Taping- Video and Adhesive Tape Activity" performance directions, photocopies of photographs, transparency., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Lines Project, Black and white contact sheets and prints. Materials include source materials, documentation of spaces, and documentation of art works, some candid and family photographs., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Artist's Postcards submission includes instructions, existing postcards, watercolor template, color photographs., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - University of Iowa installation at Corroboree Gallery, photo documentation of site and work. Materials include notes, photographs, contact sheets and negatives, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Qube Project, artists notes, articles, contact sheets, prints, and mock ups., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Black and white photographs documenting video and television artwork including the"Live!" show, Video and adhesive tape projects, and the television collection among others, ca. 1980x (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - "The Gap" black and white contact sheet, black and white prints, color photocopies and project description., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - "Evita: A Video Scrapbook" project description, black and white photographs, contact sheets, and negatives., 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - "From the Home to the Street, TV Art in New York" black and white snapshots of television graffiti, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - "From the Home to the Street" photo essay by Jaime Davidovich., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - "Evita" source material, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - "Evita" notes, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - "Evita" black and white negatives, contact sheets,and photographs documenting installation., 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Color slides of Jaime Davidovich's works ca 1986-1991. (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - "Welcome to Videoland". Black and white photograph documentation of work at Diane Brown Gallery. Photogrpah by D. James Dee., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - "Covering the Landscape" black and white photograph documenting the work at the Diane Brown Gallery. Photograph by D. James Dee., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - "Covering the Landscape" black and white photographs and negatives., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - "Debt/Deaf" installation, artist's notes and sketches., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - "Debt/Deaf" installation, production materials including decals, paper samples etc.q, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - "Debt/Deaf" installation. Photocopies of Argentine Pesos., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Debt/Deaf" installation. Black and white negatives, contact sheets, and photographs documenting the work., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - "Debt/Deaf" installation. Black and white photograph documenting the finished installation., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - "La Isla de Tesoro" [Treasure Island] artist's notes., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - "La Isla de Tesoro" [Treasure Island] production materials: yellow tissue paper., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - "La Isla de Tesoro" [Treasure Island] black and white negatives, contact sheet, and prints. Work part of the "Pervasive Symbiosis" exhibition at Carla Stellweg Gallery., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - "La Isla de Tesoro" [Treasure Island] black and white photo documentation., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - "Torn Identity" production materials: Argentine peso., 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - "Torn Identity" photograph of installation diagram., 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - "Torn Identity" black and white negatives, contact sheets, and prints of video stills., 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Artist's notes, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - "Forces/Fraces" at Exit Art. Production materials: articles, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Slides, negatives, and prints documenting the exhibition.`, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Inventory., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Slides and credit line tags., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Black and white negative and prints documenting the video installation. Photograph by Larry Lane., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - "Forces/Fraces" at Exit Art. Folder including black and white photographic documentation of the exhibit as well as publicity materials., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Question guide and responses., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - "Forces/Farces" at Exit Art. Copy of guestbook., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, floorplan, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, artist's notes., 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, polaroid panaramic collage documenting the installation., 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, black and white negatives and photographs of diaramas., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, black and white contact sheets and prints, color prints. Photodocumentation of "Los Pueblos" installation. [contact sheets are video still from "3 Mercer St", 1992 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Fundacion Banco Patricios, black and white pirnt of "Los Pueblos" installation., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - "Torn Identity" Production Materials: color snapshots., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - "Torn Identity" black and white video still large format negative and photograph., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Fundacion Antorchas, production file including floor plans and notes., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - "Point of Contact" photographs, negatives, transcript of interview with Borges, planning sketches., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - "Red, Blue, Yellow" Photodocumentation of Museo de Bellas Artes, Buenos Aires. Archive of Video Art and Experimental Film., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Scars, Pleasure, Sacrifice at Colombia Center, artist's notes., 1994 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Scars, Pleasure, Sacrifice at Colombia Center, Maxell 3.75 inch floppy. Labeled "2 sketches Colombia" Other titles crossed out including "Eye With Painting" and "AR Dollar Distorted"., ca 1994 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Scars, Pleasure, Sacrifice at Colombia Center. Production materials: Color photographs, negatives, and diagrams, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Scars, Pleasure, Sacrifice at Colombia Center. Photograph of Jaime Davidovich's contribution, "Recordando el Futuro", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Scars, Pleasure, Sacrifice at Colombia Center. Photograph and mock-up for "Recordando el Futuro", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Color negatives and photographs of studio space, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Color negatives and photographs of studio space, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - ICI Buenos Aires, black and white print of Jaime Davidovich's piece., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Photographic documentation of exhibitions at Colombia Center, Museo Del Barrio, and ICI., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - ICI Buenos Aires, slices, color negatives, and photographs of gallery space., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - ICI floorplans, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - "Yo Errancia" at ICI, black and white photographic documentation of work., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - ""La Tierra Prometida" at ICI reference for figurines, notes, black and white photograph, and photocopies., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - ICI, "La Tierra Prometida" production materials: adhesive paper, some printed with internet forum table of contents, paint chips, directions for printing., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - No Folder (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - "La Tierra Prometida" at ICI, color photo documentation., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - "La Tierra Prometida" black and white large format netatives and black and white prints., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Museo del Barrio "Artists Talk Back" exhibition. Includes artist's notes, drawings, paint chips and other planning materials., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Museo del Barrio "Artists Talk Back" exhibition. Includes black and white negatives, contact sheet, and photographs documenting the installation., 1995 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Isis Conceptual Laboratory group show, "Looking for the Pieces". Includes source material and color photographs documenting the exhibit., 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - "Zocalo" VHS sleeve. Lists the titles and production years of video art included: "Taped Project" 1970, "Road" 1972, "Bath" 1976, "Video Paintins" 1998. (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Black and white photograph of video still, labeled "Retirement Communties", used in "Zocalo", 1998 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - "Video Paintings" sketches and black and white photographs., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - "Zocalo" at Museo de Arte Moderno in Buenos Aires. Color negatives and photographs., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - "USIA 98" notes and drafts., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Video Painting. Labels, negative, and black and white prints., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Exit Art, "The End" color negatives and photographs documenting the installation, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - MALBA, photographs, slides, and notes.., 2003 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Notes about adhesive tape work., undated (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - "Jaime Davidovich Art on Tape, Tape as Art" logo, undated (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - "TV Set Art on Tape" color negatives and black and white negatives., undated (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Museo de Arte Moderna, notes., undated (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Carpet both ways, black and white photographs., undated (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - "Forces" black and white contact sheet and negatives of video stills., undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - "The Gap" black and white video still photograph., undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Garbage street, color negatives., undated (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - "Road to Nowhere, Globalism" color negatives., undated (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - "Legacy/Legado" exhibition, notes and photographs of "Inside and between", undated (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Color negatives and photographs documenting the Lehman Art Gallery space., undated (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - "Lo Falso" at ICI Buenos Aires, color photographs and artist's notes., undated (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Not in New York Gallery Show, diagram., undated (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Oil paintings, black and white photographs. Photographs by Jorge Roiger and Ivan Sani, undated (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Oil Paintings, color negatives., undated (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - "Road" videotape installation.diagrams, negatives, and photographs., undated (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - SoHo Wants to Know. Original photographs and negatives., undated (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - "SoHo, So What?" Artist notes, snapshots., undated (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - "SoHo, So What?"source material., undated (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - "SoHo, So What?" Bibliogrpahy, formatted photographs., undated (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - "Still Life" black and white negatives and contact sheet., undated (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - "3 Level" black and white negatives and contact sheet., undated (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Whitney Prepartory #1, black and white negatives, undated (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Whitney Prepartory #2, black and white negatives, undated (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Color slides, mixture of ATN, SoHo TV, the Live! Show, Jaime Davidovich's work and candid., undated (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Collected documentation of Jaime Davidovich's work: Videotape catalogue, Corroboree advertising postcard, black and white photographs, two art objects on paper., undated (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Black and white contact sheets from a variety of projects including "Road", "Baseboard" Interior"., undated (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Black and white photograph of gallery installation model., undated (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Glossy red paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Large format negatives, "Poverty", "Consumerism", and "Ecology", undated (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Color negatives and prints of video stills, undated (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - "Desire newspaper cartoons" color negatives, undated (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Color Copies of television images., undated (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - No Folder, undated (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Subseries C: Works on Paper
    - TV photograph collage., 1973 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "Tape as Art", 1974 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Art on Tape/ Tape as Art Blue taped screen on paper., 1976 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "Buy Lies" story board, 1979 (Folder 5 Left)
    - Time Magazine cover with two pencil drawings of Ronald Regan, one on either side of the cover. Magazine dated 1983., ca 1983 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - "Hiding Inside Television" Jaime Davidovich 1955, recreated February 2000. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Art sign. Color video still on heavy paper, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "Opinion" sign, oil on canvas., undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Subseries D: Exhibition Catalogs, Publicity, and Press
    - Catalog, "5 Pinturas de Jaime Davidovich" at Galeria von Riel, Buenos Aires., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 201)